Lisa Paynter

UX/UI Designer

DESIGN PROJECTS

ART FESTIVAL WEBSITE

Redesign website to meet the needs of the stakehholers, attendees, vendors and volunteers. Conduct interviews and analysis to find best organization of information for all personas. Redefined information architecture which lead to a redesign of the web layout helping create a better mobile experience.

Visual redesign layout and UI of website in a way that takes back stage to the work of the vendors. Created UI styles, colors and chose fonts to create a clean look and feel for both web and mobile use.

GOVERNMENT WEBSITE

The focus for this site was more on information architecture needs and mobile usability. I conducted user interviews and heruistic evealuations along with red lines of problem areas concerning specific design flaws and task needs. Wireframes and UI redesign was created from scratch for this site last designed in 1998.

TRAVEL APP

WORK EXPERIENCE

LEAD DESIGNER AND MARKETING SPECIALIST

2016 - PRESENT

Wright-Hennepin Cooperative Electric Association

Designer of print and web communications. Create and support brand strategies for WH and its subsidiaries by clarifying brand messaging, which include personas, value propositions, and journey mapping.

FREELANCE DESIGNER

2014 - 2017

Freelance projects include design and production work for print for BI Worldwide, Padilla, Signature Bank, FLM, Customer Centered Strategies, Sandy's Photo Booth, Career Management Services, Capstone, and Quarto.

SENIOR GRAPHIC DESIGNER

2007 - 2014

TE Connectivity (formerly ADC)

Design and layout of long and short documents including brochures, catalogs, spec sheets, white papers, email, magazine ads, and web graphics. Special projects included:

- set-up of online print on demand system for TE in USA
- choosing and organizing a project management system for global use between marketing communication specialists and designers (Clarizen)
- Design and creation of templates/styles for literature system
- Implemented a secure digital asset manager for global corporate use
- Extensive involvement with the development and launch of website

CONTACT ME

lisa.paynter3@gmail.com 763-412-7768

SKILLS

Visual design Typography Branding digital and print design systems personas User insights Journey mapping usability testing storyboarding messaging guides prototyping wireframing card sorting Information architecture touchpoint mapping affinity diagrams Affinity mapping **Empathy mapping** Insight creation

TOOLS

Figma XD

InDesign

Illustrator

Photoshop

Acrobat Salesforce

Bridge

Microsoft

Google

Basecamp/Jira/InMotion/Trello

INTERSTS

Gardening | Food Kayaking | Hiking | Geocaching Behavioral neuroscience Needle arts | Almost everything

EDUCATION

Mini Master of Marketing Management St. Thomas, Minneapolis, MN

Social Media Certificate Minneapolis Community Technical College, Minneapolis, MN

Associate in Applied Science — Graphic Design, County College of Morris, Randolph, NJ